前情提要
塔尔萨之王
你是新手司机吗
So, you a new driver?
前情提要
塔尔萨之王
我刚从纽约搬来
I just relocated from New York.
我80年代去过一次纽约
I went to New York once in the '80s.
-最鼎盛的年代  -我跟我父母
- The heyday. - Parents and I got mugged
被一个拿武士刀的抢劫了
by a guy with a samurai sword.
也不是所有人都喜欢
It's not for everybody.
你在参加驾考 在等红灯时
So, you're at the light taking your driver's test,
-然后  -趴下
- and then... - Down!
我们在系统里查过你名字
You know we ran your name through the system.
-那你一定知道我是个狮子座  -他可以走了
- Then you know I'm a Leo. - He's free to go.
他身上还有更重要的调查
Part of a bigger investigation.
你来鸟不拉屎的俄克拉荷马做什么
What are you doing here in Cow Patty, Oklahoma?
除恶扬善 保卫中西部呗
Stopping bad guys from blowing up our country.
这里工作不好做吧
Tough day at the office.
塔尔萨是烟酒火器管理局的众多流放地之一
Tulsa is one of the ATF's many versions of Siberia.
这是什么 你看像不像是FR
What's that? Look like "FR" to you?
离这里大概五英里远
Place about five miles from here.
-费纳尼奥太太  -叫我德维洛小姐就行
- Mrs. Fennario? - Miss Devereaux.
有辆车被偷后又被烧毁
Car was stolen and set on fire,
这是我在后座找到的
and I found this in the backseat.
-我是私家侦探  -那我还是个航天员呢
- I'm a private investigator. - Right, and I'm an astronaut.
你介意我四处问问吗
Well, do you mind if I ask around?
在我的地盘上吗 当然介意
On my property? Yeah, I do mind.
没毛病
Fair enough.
里奇 悠着点
Oh, Ritchie, easy.
拜托别让她速度超过160
Keep her under 160, for Christ sake.
得了吧 曼尼 她都没出汗
Come on Manny, she ain't even gonna break a sweat.
三天后还有场小马驹比赛
She's got a baby race in three days.
我想让她在周六前保持体力
I want a little sugar left in the tank still come Saturday.
这么心疼 还不如用她去拉巡游花车
Seems like you're gearing her more for a hay ride.
她要是在比赛中成绩不好
Yeah, well, it ain't you getting ripped a new one
被老板骂的又不是你
if she goes flat ahead of the stretch.
再骑五分钟 就让她休息
Ten more minutes, then cool her down.
-你准备走了吗  -去去就回
- You headed out? - Yeah, I'll be back.
家里有事处理
Just got some shit at home to deal with.
I'm living paycheck to paycheck
我入不敷出 勉强维系
My money's all gone
拆东墙补西墙
你好 宝贝
Hey, babe.
送完孩子后我要去趟廉价超市
I'm gonna swing by WinCo after I drop the boys.
需要带什么吗
You want anything?
他觉得很好笑是吧
Thinks it's a fucking joke.
行吧 要是买错了麦片
Okay, well, don't complain
到时候别怪我
when I don't remember what cereal you wanted.
-什么  -去去就回
- What? - I'll be back in a bit.
草泥马的混蛋
Motherfucking bastard.
我他妈要杀了他
Fucking hit him.
-后备箱关上  -老天 我就知道
Close the trunk. - Jesus, I knew it.
我早他妈知道
I fucking knew it.
跪下
Get on your knees.
我会提到一个名字
I'm gonna say a name,
你只用是和否来回答
and you're gonna answer me yes or no.
就这么简单 齐齐
It's very simple. Chickie.
齐齐 齐齐怎么了
Chickie? What about Chickie?
-转过来  -我不知
- Turn around. - I don't...
马上交代 不然我一枪
Better start talking or I promise your brains
让你脑花溅厨房
are gonna be all over this fucking kitchen.
齐齐什么 我他妈根本不知道
Chickie what? I got no fucking idea
你到底在问什么 哪个齐齐
what you're asking me. Chickie what?
你把话说完 我保证马上交代
Just tell me and I'll tell you, please.
是他派你来杀我的吗 是不是
Did he send you here to kill me, yes or no?
不不 我都20年没见过齐齐了
No! No, I haven't even seen Chickie in over 20 years.
-那是谁指使你的  -指使我
- So, who hired you? - Hired me?
我都听不懂你在说什么
I don't even know what you're talking about.
睁眼说瞎话 那天要杀我的人
You gonna tell me that wasn't you
不是你吗
who tried to take me out the other day?
-谁指使你的  -你跑来塔尔萨要杀我
- Who sent you? - You came here to kill me.
我还能怎么办 坐以待毙吗
What the fuck was I supposed to do, wait?
我有老婆有孩子
I got a wife, I got kids.
我在商场看到你了 以为齐齐
When I saw you at the mall, I figured Chickie's the one
派你来杀我了
who sent you here to kill me.
我本人跟你没过节 德怀特
I got no beef with you, Dwight.
跟你 纽约 和你们那群人都没过节
Not you, not New York, not fucking anybody.
但让我问问 你他妈来塔尔萨干嘛
But Jesus Christ, why the fuck else would you be in Tulsa?
-有糖吗  -什么
- Sugar? - What?
你家有糖吗
You got sugar?
没有 我们有龙舌兰糖浆
No, we have-what do you call it, agave.
-那是啥  -不知道
- The fuck's that? - No idea.
所以我来捋一捋啊
So, let me get this right.
我来到这个偏远的小地方
I'm here in the middle of nowhere,
好巧不巧
and just by some coincidence,
你竟然也在这 你以为我是来杀你的
you're here too, and you try to shoot me
所以决定先下手为强
because you think I'm here to shoot you?
这就是你的辩护词吗
Is that the line of defense you're going with?
我以我孩子起誓
On my kid's eyes, I fucking swear,
都是千真万确的事实
it's the Gods honest truth.
老婆马上就回来
My wife's gonna be home any minute now.
-她什么都不知情  -我会给她留张便条的
She doesn't know anything. - I'll leave a note.
蒂克·塔瓦雷斯
Tico Tavares.
-什么  -蒂克·塔瓦雷斯
- What? - Tico Tavares.
-他怎么了  -他们在监狱里陷害了你
- What about him? - In prison, they set you up.
我想要警告你 但没成功
I tried to warn you but I couldn't get through.
你说他们想陷害我
You said they tried to set me up.
-他们是谁  -皮特
- Who's they? - Pete.
我兄弟皮特
My Pete?
-你撒谎  -他担心你会翻供
- You fucking liar. - He was afraid you'd flipped.
毕竟判了25年啊
Fucking 25 years, come on.
谁能忍受蹲那么久
Nobody does that kind of time.
-我  -我知道
- I did. - I know you did,
但大多数人都觉得
but most of these guys...
我知道了这些 怕被他们灭口
I was afraid they'd kill me because of what I knew.
所以我才逃走了
That's why I skipped town.
我已经在这住了19年 德怀特 有了新生活
I've been here 19 years, Dwight. I built a life.
皮特
Pete...
你家草坪是自己修的吗
You mow your lawn?
-什么  -你自己割草吗
- What? - Do you mow your grass?
-当然  -我从没
- Yeah, sure. - You know, I've never...
修剪过草坪 这辈子都没有
mowed a lawn, never. Not once in my entire life.
你在布鲁克林长大
You grew up in Brooklyn, so.
德怀特 很抱歉 我没告发任何人
Dwight, I'm sorry. I didn't rat on anybody.
也没伤害任何人 我只想退出
I didn't want to hurt nobody. I just wanted out.
你知道 规矩不是这样的
You know that ain't the way it goes, right?
阿曼德 你在25年前
Our thing, 25 years ago, Armand,
就搞砸了
you fucked up,
我奉献了自己三分之一的人生
and I went away for what became a third of my life.
而你
And then you...
却想一枪置我于死地
tried to put a bullet in my head.
我对天发誓
I-- I swear to God,
-我只想  -我还没说完
- I was just trying... - I'm talking.
你今后为我卖命 懂了吗 就跟你以前一样
You work for me now, understand? Like you always have.
今后每周六都要交上缴份额
I expect an envelope every Saturday.
从300开始
We'll start at 300 bucks a week.
德怀特 这里是塔尔萨 跟纽约不一样
Dwight, this ain't New York. It's fucking Tulsa.
谁叫你搬到这里的
I didn't tell you to move here.
我就晚来了这一次
Of course, the one time I am running late.
我会给你们送点糖
I'll send over some sugar.
天啊
Oh my God.
字幕来源   网络
字幕整理   fantastic612
字幕调轴
小米勾勾
字幕特效  猪小乐
塔尔萨之王
第一季
第4集
知道吗 你做得不对
You know you're doing that wrong.
你体态不对
Your form.
嘿 哥们
Hey, pal.
-你说啥  -朋友
- Sorry. - Buddy.
壶铃
The kettlebells.
不是这么举的
You're not lifting them right.
是吗
Really?
-膝盖放松  -嗯
- Soft knees. - Mm-hmm?
你得带动臀部
You got to hinge your hips.
让身体平直 保持站立
Keep your body in a standing plank position.
-然后再举  -不如这样
- And lift. - I'll tell you what.
我给这个过程加点乐子
Let's make it interesting.
你站在我面前
You stand in front of me,
我挥出一拳 如果不把你干趴下
and if I can't put you to sleep with one swing,
我就给你最喜欢的慈善机构捐一千
I'll donate a grand to your favorite charity.
同意吗
Deal?
还是让我按错误方式继续
Or should I go back to doing it wrong?
蓝穹男装店
Blue Dome Haberdashery.
量体裁衣 咱们去这里看看
Custom tailoring. Let's try that.
我这些西服想拿去改一下
I wanna drop these suits off to get altered.
这挂的是什么
What the hell's that?
电子应答器 计费用的
It's a transponder. For tolls.
-免停车交费  -扔了
- It's like an easy pass. - Get rid of it.
他们只会给你车牌拍张照
They just gonna take a picture of the license plate,
把账单寄家里
send a bill in the mail.
最好别扔吧
You don't get rid of that.
那我希望他们能拍到我上镜的那一面
I hope they get my good side.
不能让他们那么轻松
Let's not make it too easy for them.
我先来瞧瞧效果
Let's see what we got here.
-好嘞  -好
- Okay. - All right.
知道吗 肯尼·罗杰斯来塔尔萨时常来光顾我家
You know, Kenny Rogers used to shop here when he was in town.
■
肯尼·罗杰斯（1938-2020），美国知名歌手、词曲作者、演员、唱片制作人、企业家
-哪个肯尼  -连他都不知道
- Kenny who? - Seriously?
这家伙进过名人堂的
The guy's in the Hall of Fame.
真正的勇士永远知道何时进退
Know when to hold them. Know when to fold them.
■
肯尼·罗杰斯《The Gambler》单曲中的歌词
我看看能怎么搭配
Let's see what we got here.
我好像比之前胖了些
I seem to have expanded a little bit.
我能说实话吗
Can I be honest with you?
这里是塔尔萨
We're in Tulsa.
来点更现代风的如何
How about something a little more modern?
突出本地风格的
More in keeping with the local style?
一件这样的夹克 配斯泰森帽
A jacket like this with a Stetson
再穿双卢切斯靴子 呜呼
and a pair of Lucchese Boots, hoo-wee,
你会走路都带风的
you would look like a million bucks.
这衣服上面是鳄鱼吧 哥们儿
There's alligators up on that motherfucker, man.
是 这上面有只鳄鱼
Yeah, it's an alligator.
你怎么能拒绝鳄鱼呢
You can't turn that down, it's got the alligators.
我这身跟鳄鱼不搭配
Alligators don't work on this.
施展你的魔法
Work your magic.
-把衣服改合身就行  -没问题
- Just make them fit. - Done.
不过呢 一个从不换风格的人 肯定有个糟糕裁缝
However, the man who only suits himself has a fool for a tailor.
-我听过更难听的  -知道吗 有次格莱美颁奖礼
- I've been called worse. - You know, a couple Grammys ago,
吹牛老爹穿了一条杜嘉班纳的印花衬衫裙子
Puffy pulled up with the paisley Dolce and Gabbana.
你要也这么穿 肯定潮爆全场
You know you'd be fly as shit in that, man?
你能上前一步来吗
Can you step a little bit closer?
-怎么了  -摆拍 对焦
- Hey, what's up? - Bang. Zoom.
谢谢了 伯特
Thank you, Bert.
来 你看这家伙
Hey, look at this guy.
他做什么了
Hm. What'd he do?
-还没有  -什么意思
- Nothing yet. - What does that mean?
你在问什么
What do you mean?
-他是罪犯吗  -不 这是在探探上看的
- Is he a perp? - No, he's on Tinder.
纳税人的辛苦钱就是让你做这个的哈
So happy to see our hard earned tax dollars at work.
-怎么 你没上么  -没
- Oh, you're not online? - No, I'm not.
别这样 又不是啥大事
Come on, it's not terrible.
跟淘金有点像
It's kind of like panning for gold.
运气好就能挖到金块
Sometimes you find a nugget.
看来还是我太守旧了
I guess I'm old-fashioned.
我更喜欢亲眼看到老二
I actually have to get my dick picks in person.
是吗 那也得能看到啊
Oh, how's that going?
拜托 史黛西 你总要约会的
Come on, Stacy, you get out there a little bit.
我最近约过
Yeah, I was out there recently.
不那么顺利 不过我没事
It didn't go great. I'm fine.
行吧 别让我担心你
Hey, don't make me worry about you.
搞来这些东西没遇到困难吧
Any trouble getting these things?
当然没有 监管这些东西的
Fuck no. Nitrous is overseen
是食药监局
by the Food and Drug Administration.
不是什么让人生畏的单位
Not exactly the agency that strikes fear in one's heart.
-完全正确  -对吧
- Not exactly. - No, right?
德怀特 准备好了吗
Dwight, we ready?
泰森在路上了
Tyson is on his way.
你们想喝点什么吗
You guys want something to drink?
-好的  -不了 我们还有正事要干
- Yes. - No, we're working.
-真是的  -好了
- Come on. - Okay.
德怀特 你还记得疤脸吗
Hey, Dwight, you remember Bad Face?
那个大麻农场的神经病
Yeah, the psycho neurotic from the weed farm.
是
Yeah.
他接下来几天要过来送货
He's in town for the next couple days making some drops.
你也许不想跟他打照面
So, I thought maybe you'd want to avoid him.
不不不 我对疤脸没意见
No, no, no, I got no issue with Bad Face.
你一定要见见他 奇葩得很
You gotta see this guy, he's definitely off the reservation.
-这人什么来路  -是个克里克印第安人
- Who is he? - He's a Creek Indian
爱盯着你看
with a staring problem.
-会盯得你发毛  -派对上最需要这种人
- Serious staring problem. - Sounds fun at parties.
-战争派对吧  -准备出发了吗
- Yeah, war parties. - Ready to roll out?
好了 给后备箱装上货
All right, throw that stuff in the trunk
大家出去搞钱去
and go out there and make some money.
-是 长官  -好嘞
- Yes, sir. - Okay.
加油干 孩子们
Go get 'em kids.
该死的疤脸
Fucking Bad Face.
-冰凉肉排  -就这样10刀到手
- Ice-cold patties. Here you go, that's 10 bucks.
记得抓紧气球一头
Hey, hold it at the tip,
别让里面的气跑掉
you gonna lose all the good stuff, now.
-瞧瞧这人山人海  -生意不错啊
- Look at these motherfuckers. - Business is booming.
是啊 要买气球吗
Oh, yeah. You guys want a balloon?
谁说你们可以在这里开店了
Who the fuck said you could set up here?
停车场啊
The parking lot?
不 谁允许你们卖气球的
No, like, who gave you permission to sell?
没人允许
Nobody gave us permission to sell.
因为我们也没问啊
'cause we ain't asking for permission.
这是我们的地盘
This is our territory.
你们要买东西吗
You want to buy something?
慢走
Bye-bye.
我上次喝酒已经是15年前了
Fifteen years since I had my last drink,
我真谢谢你
so thank you for that.
就在德文出生前 没错
Right before Devin was born, yeah.
-他会杀我们吗  -不会杀你跟孩子
- Will he kill us? - Not you and the kids.
-不会  -原来这就是博伊西的意义
- No. - That's what Boise was about?
所以你给我们留下了什么
So, what have you left us?
你什么意思 房子人寿保险之类的吗
What do you mean? Like, the house? Life insurance?
不 我是指我们 你和我
No, us. You and me.
我今后还怎么相信
Because how am I supposed to believe anything
你口里的任何话
that you tell me from this point out?
你他妈就是个骗子 曼尼
'Cause you're a fucking liar, Manny.
-你真叫这个名字吗  -我叫阿曼德
- Is that even really your name? - It's Armand.
-你知道的  -真的吗
- You know that. - Do I?
拜托 别这么多咄咄逼人 克拉拉
Oh, come on, would you fucking stop, please, Clara?
对不起 你是对的
I'm sorry. You're right.
我们初次见面时我就该告诉你一切
I should've told you everything when we first met,
告诉你我的过去 但我们在一起的时间越久
about my past, but the further down the line we got,
我就感觉越没必要
the less necessary it felt.
都是尘封往事了
It was like ancient history
坦白讲 我宁愿忘记
that I, frankly, I wanted to forget.
因为不堪回首
It's ugly.
我现在知道了
I know now.
我总算是知道了
Now I do.
怎么样
How'd it go?
十瓶气都卖完了
We went through all ten of the tanks.
-不错  -本来还可以卖更多
- Yeah. - We could've sold more
-但只带了十瓶  -笑气这玩意儿
- if we had them. - Laughing gas.
让我们一路笑到银行 哈哈
Laughing all the way to the bank, huh?
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
今晚还有活动吗
Something going on tonight?
对 明晚也有
Yeah, and tomorrow night, too.
好吧 我们去趟米奇那儿
All right, let's swing by Mitch's
多取几瓶来
and pick up some more tanks.
拿着
Here.
买点好看的东西奖励自己
Buy yourself something pretty.
我可能会买个你那种戒指
I might get me one of them rings.
知道吗 我这个已经戴旧了
You know what? This one has lost its luster.
-送你吧  -你认真的
- Here, take it. - You serious?
当然 拿去 你应得的
Yeah, take it. Come on, you earned it.
我去
Fuck.
所以
So...
要是我没听错的话 小伙子们
if I'm hearing right-- and lads, by all means,
我要说错 你们随时打断我
jump in and stop me if you feel different.
你跟戴维就让他们大摇大摆地走了进来
You and Davy here, you just let them waltz on in.
支起摊子 你俩什么都没做
Come in, come in and you let them
让他们从我们手里抢吃的
take the food right off our table.
-我说的对吗  -我们觉得不跟你商量
- Did I get that right? - We didn't think it wise
就动手不太合适
to start any shit without checking with you first.
怂的一批
Weak fucking links.
他们扛不起事 优柔寡断
They're unreliable, indecisive,
现在更是彻头彻尾的怂逼
and now revealed to be total pussies.
怂的一批
Weak fucking links.
就这么被几个搅局的嬉皮士截胡了
Easily exploited by interloping hippies.
我们连自己地盘都守不住 像什么样子
I mean, who are we if we can't protect what's ours?
他们让我们陷入被动
They've left us all exposed.
你们
This.
犯得不是小错 不
It's no minor fuck up. No.
这件事
This is a threat
威胁到了我们的存亡
to our very existence.
你就为这事打断我吃早餐
You interrupted my breakfast for this?
德怀特 这是古董啊 19世纪的
Dwight, it's an antique. It's like 19th century.
纯铜的 你看过《美国拾荒者》吗
Pure copper. You ever see American Pickers?
大家对这玩意儿趋之若鹜
People go crazy for this shit.
是呢 所有美国家庭的必需品
Sure, what household couldn't live without one of these?
我是说 你可以把它卖了
I'm just saying, you could sell it,
能值两万块
could be worth, like, 20 grand.
-你怎么不卖  -我卖不掉
- So, you sell it. - I can't sell it,
他们会知道是我偷的
they'll know I stole it.
我去卖 人家会怀疑是我偷的
If I sell it, they'll think I stole it.
你这些年铲马屎是不是把脑子铲坏了
I think shoveling horse shit has affected your brain, Armand.
拜托 德怀特 我真的绞尽脑汁了
Come on, Dwight, please. I'm trying over here.
我尽力了 别苛责我
I'm really trying. Give me a break.
在被人发现之前
Take it back there before someone looks up
原样不动还回去
and sees it's missing.
我要的是现金
Cash, Armand.
为了偷它 我差点把脖子摔断
I nearly broke my neck getting that thing down.
该死
Fuck!
婚礼什么时候举行
When's the wedding?
-什么  -你手上戴的
- What? - Are you telling me that ain't
不是订婚戒指吗
an engagement ring on your finger?
老爹 你真幽默 今天心情不错哈
Oh, you got-- you funny. You got jokes today, right?
这之前是我老板的
It was-- it was my boss'.
-为什么之前是  -他送给我了
- What you mean "was"? - He gave it to me
为了表彰我对工作的投入
to acknowledge the hard work I've been putting in.
作为司机
As a chauffeur?
不只是司机 老爸
It's more than a chauffeur, Dad, I'm--
-我还保护他安全  -保护他什么安全
- I'm also like security, too. - Protecting him from what?
他是个成功人士 老爸
Whatever, you know, he's a successful guy, you know.
会招来羡慕嫉妒恨的
People get jealous of him.
-这人是黑帮吧  -马克
- This man a mobster? - Mark.
你干嘛非要这么说
Why would you even say something like that?
只有两类人戴尾戒
Only two types of people wear pinky rings--
黑帮和英国贵族
mobsters and British aristocracy.
我估摸着你老板不能是英国贵族吧
And something tells me your boss ain't no aristocrat.
你都意识不到这话他妈的多偏见
That's some real prejudiced shit right there, I don't know
-吃饭不许说脏话  -马克 让孩子好好吃饭行吗
- Hey, language at my table. - Mark, let the boy eat.
泰森能分清对错
Tyson knows right from wrong.
-上面的钻石是真的吗  -当然是
- That a real diamond, Ty? - Of course it is.
随便你吧 爸
Whatever you say, Dad.
你好
Hello?
乔 是我
Jo, it's me.
你声音苍老了许多
Christ, you sound old.
听到你声音我也很高兴
It's great hearing your voice, too.
毕竟都25年了
Twenty-five years.
你期望我能说啥
What do you expect?
-听说你联系了蒂娜  -对
- I heard you called Tina? - Yeah.
如果你希望我去劝劝她
Well, if you're looking for me to intervene,
那你找错人了
you're barking up the wrong tree.
我几乎很少见她
I hardly ever see her myself.
不过说实话 我几个小时之后会见到她
Truth be told, I'm gonna see her in a couple of hours.
是吗
Yeah?
那很好啊
That's-- that's nice, good.
是乔伊的事
It's Joe.
他得了淋巴瘤
He's got lymphoma.
我们在轮流照顾他
And we all take turns doing shifts.
我也过去吧
Should-- should I come?
有用吗 现在吗
What for? Now?
他也是我兄弟啊 我们的兄弟
He's still my brother. Our brother.
你这是干什么 这是什么分步心理治疗
What are you, in some bullshit step program
完成道歉之旅吗
doing your apology tour?
你能不能别挑我毛病 哪怕就一会儿
You want to stop busting my balls for about five seconds?
那我再问你一次
So I'm gonna ask you again.
什么是现在
Why now?
讲真 我也不知道
Honestly, I don't know.
我说不清
I don't know anything.
你他妈真是个人物 知道吗
You're a real fucking beaut, you know that?
杳无音信晾了我们25年
Radio silence for 25 years.
我会跟你更新乔的情况
I'll keep you posted about Joe.
当心 各位
Hey, heads up, y'all. Hey, look,
我早跟你们这帮混蛋讲过
we told y'all motherfuckers that we--
别这样 哥们
Come on, man.
别这样啊
Come on! Come on!
我跟佛罗里达奥卡拉的一个房产中介
I scheduled a Zoom with a real estate agent...
约了视频会
from Ocala, Florida.
是吗 那里倒是有很多马场
Oh yeah? That's-- that's horse country.
对 我也不敢保证什么
Yeah, I'm not promising anything.
就
It's just...
就先谈一谈 仅此而已
worth a conversation, that's all.
真他妈难以置信
Fucking unbelievable.
是那群说需要许可的人打得你们吗
So, these are the same guys that said you needed permission?
那天晚上的那群人
The guys from the other night?
是 另外还来了五个人
It was them, and it was five other guys.
六个
Six.
拿走了我们的气罐 现金 一切
They took our tanks, our cash, all of it.
很抱歉 老大
I'm so sorry about that, man.
没什么好抱歉的
You've got nothing to be sorry about.
你坚守了阵地 但输了 现在该重振旗鼓了
You held your ground, you lost. Now it's time to regroup.
-他们有说老板是谁吗  -没
- They say who they work for? - No.
没 但几个人的夹克上
No, but a couple of guys had
绣着 黑碎石
Black Macadam embroidered on their jackets.
是当地的摩托帮
A local biker gang.
-厉害吗  -不容小觑
- They anything? - Well, they ain't nothing.
好吧 那我们该怎么做
All right, so what we finna do?
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
有一件事显而易见
We're gonna do the obvious thing.
我们要进去夺回气罐
We're gonna go in there, we're gonna get our tanks,
拿回属于我们的钱
and then we're gonna get our money.
-我不参与暴力  -我们不搞暴力
- I don't do violence. - We're not doing violence.
我们拼的是脑筋 你读过《孙子兵法》吗
We're using our head. You ever read The Art of War?
都兵法了
Wouldn't you say that war
还不属于暴力范畴吗
falls under the violence category here?
孙子言 不战而胜 善之善者
Quote, "the greatest victories are obtained without battle."
所以 开动脑筋的时刻来了
End quote. We're gonna use our heads.
-是吗  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
行吧 但以防万一 我还是带上疤脸吧
Fine, but I'm gonna bring Bad Face just in case.
什么事 德怀特
Yeah, Dwight?
我要你今晚七点来
I need you to meet me at seven tonight
生而叛逆酒吧见我 知道吗
at the Bred-2-Buck. You know it?
-什么事  -什么事
- What's up? - What's up?
我要给你一个
I'm giving you a chance to pay back
将功赎过的机会
some of what you owe me.
不不不 谢了 不过
No, no, no, thank you, but...
七点啊 阿曼德
Seven, Armand.
我辛辛苦苦把你养大成人
This is what I worked my ass off for.
-送你上大学  -我就跟人打了一架 爸
- Send you to college. - I just got into a fight, Dad.
扯淡 都是你为那个
Bullshit. This happened
该死的罪犯工作闹的
'cause you work for that goddamn criminal.
-马克 事情还不清楚  -不 也许你不清楚
- Mark, we don't know that. - No, maybe you don't know.
但我清楚 泰森也清楚
But I do. And Tyson sure does.
告诉你妈妈 泰森
Tell your mom Tyson, hm?
直视她双眼 对她撒谎
Look in her eye and lie to her face,
你现在不就这两下子吗
'cause that's how you do now, right?
你根本不懂自己在说什么
You don't even know what you're talking about.
行啊 那你来教教我
All right, so enlighten me.
我洗耳恭听 你到底因为什么打起架的
Enlighten me. What was this big fight about?
是你所谓的安保工作吧
Is this your security work?
如果是的话 我看
'Cause if it is, it looks to me
你才是那个需要保护的人
like you're the one need protecting.
你总觉得我没法安身立命
You always thinking that I can't handle my own.
好像承受不了任何压力
Like I can't handle any type of pressure...
别别别 别把自己
No, no, no, you don't get to turn this
说成受害者
into you're the victim.
-选好了路 就要坚持下去  -我试过 真的
- Pick a lane, son. - I tried, it's true.
我试过大学 但我的专业太弱智了
I tried to go to college. My major was too imbecilic.
-我没说错吧  -你都没读完
- Was I wrong? - You didn't even finish.
白白浪费我们辛苦挣来的每一次机会
Made nothing out of every opportunity we provided you.
-我在努力了 爸爸  -帮黑帮开车吗
- I'm trying, Dad. - By driving some gangster's car?
你都25岁了 泰森
You're 25, Tyson.
你妈妈跟我还要等多久
How long are your mother and I supposed to wait
才能看到投资你的回报
before we see a return on our investment?
你们想要回报是吗
Oh, you want a return, huh?
来 回报给你
Oh, I got a return for you.
这样行了吗 可以吗
How about this? How is that?
-泰森  -给你五秒钟
- Tyson. - You got five seconds
从我面前消失 丢人现眼的玩意儿
to get your ass and that out of my sight.
泰森 泰森
Tyson. Tyson!
-旋律不错  -随便弹弹罢了
- That's catchy. - Oh, just a little fiddling.
梅奇会帮我替班
Maisie's gonna cover for me.
咱们什么时候能回来
What time you think we're gonna be back?
从哪回来
From where?
-音乐会啊  -你不是还在保释期吗
- From the concert. - Aren't you on parole?
没有我 你们能行吗
You don't think you're going without me, do you?
不不 你留下 你绝不能被抓
No, no, you gotta stay here. You're not getting busted.
在吧台遥祝我们胜利就好 我们能行
Work your magic behind the bar. We got this.
嘿 好久不见
Hey, haven't seen you in a minute.
我最近都是在我家沙发的陪伴下
Eh, I've mostly been drinking
自饮自酌
with my close friend, the couch, lately.
我觉得该打破循环了
Trying to break the cycle.
很高兴能协助你打破循环 龙舌兰加冰 对吧
Happy to help you process. Casamigos, rocks?
是的没错
Yes, please.
有大杯的吗
Is it possible to get that in a large size?
我看看能不能给你找个大杯
Let me see if I can find you a Big Gulp.
哦 谢谢 真是帮大忙了
Oh, thank you. You are doing God's work.
不用了 吧台那头的朋友帮你付了
No need, your friend at the end of the bar covered it.
上菜
Order up!
德怀特 米奇在哪儿
Dwight. Where's Mitch?
干嘛
Why?
就是 感觉这兆头不妙
I mean, you know, it just feels like a bad omen.
这才不是
It's not a bad omen.
我说了 这就像是外科手术
I told you this is gonna be surgical.
非暴力 我们要用的是我们的头脑
Nonviolent, we're using our head.
相信我
Trust me on that.
-D先生  -嗯
- Mr. D? - Yeah.
我朋友不多
I ain't got a lot of friends, so this means
所以你把我也算进来对我意义重大
a lot to me that you've included me in this beat down.
-咱们开干吧  -开干
- Hoka hey. - Hoka hey.
我准备好了 让我们开始吧
I'm ready to roll. Let's get it cracking.
-都拿齐了吗  -已经在车里了
- Got everything? - It's already in the car.
好 走吧
All right, let's do it.
-泰森  -草
- Tyson. - Oh, shit.
那是谁
Who's that?
等我一下 德怀特 我去处理一下
Just give me one second, Dwight. Let me handle this real quick.
你他妈的干什么 你跟踪我过来的吗
What the hell are you doing? Did you follow me here?
不是 我叫导航给我找到最笨的白痴
No, I just set my GPS to dumbass motherfucker.
爸爸 我现在正忙呢
Dad, I'm in the middle of something right now.
-你看得出来 对吧  -具体忙什么
- You can see that, right? - Which is what, exactly?
-赶紧结束  -别对我儿子指手画脚
Wrap it up. - Don't tell my son what to do.
冷静 爸 放松一点
Whoa, whoa, chill, Dad. Relax a little bit.
你儿子为我工作
Your son works for me.
我儿子很正派 教养良好
My boy is decent, raised right.
你儿子不再是小孩了 他是个大人了
Your boy ain't a boy anymore, he's a man.
我说了 他在为我工作
And like I said, he works for me.
-你来还是不来  -爸爸 我们
- You coming or not? - Dad, we...
谁打了我儿子
Who put that beating on my son?
已经在算账了
It's being taken care of.
你现在是要去那里吗
Is that where you're off to now?
-去算账吗  -那是待办事项之一
- To take care of things? - It's on the list.
-那我也去  -爸 你什么意思
- Then I'm coming too. - Dad, what do you mean?
敌人的敌人就是我的朋友（《孙子兵法》）
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
如果你要带这支军队上战场 那相信我
And if this is the army you're bringing into battle,
你需要所有你能找到的朋友
then trust me, you need all the friends you can get.
他是认真的
He's serious.
你当爸爸了吗
- You a father? - Mm-mmm.
那你为什么还要问
Then why are you asking questions
你知道答案的问题
you already know the answer to?
德怀特
Dwight.
你好吗 马克
How you doing? Mark.
开始吧 马克 来吧
Let's hit it, Mark. Come on!
纽约女孩来到俄克拉何马州
So, the New York girl comes to Oklahoma
惩恶扬善啊
to fight the bad guys.
嗯 就像童话故事里一样
Yeah, just like in the fairy tales.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
科尔顿 你有什么故事
So, what's your story, Colton?
所见即所得
What you see is what you get.
真的吗 好吧 那是什么
Oh, really? Okay, yeah, well, what is that?
-和一个好男人共度美好时光  -你是个好人吗
- Good time with a good guy. - Are you a good guy?
我希望我是
I like to think I am.
好
All right.
快点 演出要结束了
Come on the show's almost over.
我们怎么不进去
We should go on ahead in. What's going on?
阿什佩特 让他们先帮我们收钱
Ashpet, let 'em collect our money first.
-德怀特  -嗯
- Dwight? - Yeah.
他们有12个
There's twelve of them.
那可是我的幸运数字啊
That's my lucky fucking number.
我们只有八个人
There's only eight of us.
你连你自己都算啊
You seriously counting yourself?
德怀特 告诉我你的计划不会
Dwight, tell me you have a plan that doesn't involve
让我脸上再挨一拳
me getting punched in the face again.
我有计划 别紧张
I got a plan, relax.
我想提个建议
I'd like to propose something.
当然可以 弗雷德 你说
Sure, Fred, what is it?
克林特和我进去
Clint and I are gonna go in,
激怒他们 胡说八道
rile 'em up, start talking shit.
-等等等等  -闭嘴 好吧
- Wait, wait, wait. - Shut up. All right.
当他们向我们逼近时 我们就给信号 好吗
When they advance on us, we give a signal, okay?
你们都从侧翼包过来 然后猛击膝盖
Y'all come in from the flank and you can take them out
干掉他们 好吗
at the fucking knees, all right?
-我喜欢 弗雷德  -对吧
- I like it, Fred. - Right?
-嗯  -不要
- Yeah. - No!
德怀特 拜托告诉我你有实际点的计划
Dwight, please tell me you have an actual plan.
将军大计在握 菩提
The general's got a plan, Bodhi.
《孙子兵法》中说过
The Art of War states that eventually
每个男人最终都得有种
each man has gotta grow a set of balls.
走吧 孩子们
Let's go, my children.
■
《War》
Edwin Starr
War, huh, yeah
战争
What is it good for?
有什么好处
Absolutely nothing
完全没有
War, huh, yeah
战争
What is it good for?
有什么好处
Absolutely nothing
完全没有
Say it again, y'all
大家 再来一遍
War, huh, look out
战争 小心
What is it good for?
有什么好处
Absolutely nothing, listen to me
完全没有 听我说
Oh, war, I despise
我唾弃战争
'Cause it means destruction of innocent lives
因为战争 意味着无辜生命的毁灭
War means tears to thousands of mother's eyes
战争意味着千千万万母亲
When their sons go off to fight
会在他们的儿子去打仗
And lose their lives
丢掉性命的时候流泪
I said war, huh
我说了战争
Good God, y'all
上帝啊 你说
What is it good for?
它有什么好处
Absolutely nothing, just say it again
绝对没好处 再说一遍
War(whoa), huh(oh Lord)
战争 啊
What is it good for?
它有什么好处
Absolutely nothing, listen to me
绝对没有 听我说
War, it ain't nothing but a heartbreaker
战争 它只会让人心碎
War, friend only to the undertaker
战争 只是殡葬业的朋友
Oh, war, it's an enemy to all mankind
战争 它是全人类的敌人
The thought of war blows my mind
想到战争我就心惊胆战
War has caused unrest
战争在年轻的一代中
Within the younger generation
引起动乱
Induction then destruction
创造然后毁灭
Who wants to die?
谁会想死
Oh, war
哦 战争
Good God, y'all
上帝啊 各位
What is it good for?
它有什么好处
Absolutely nothing
完全没有
Say it, say it, say it
说吧 说吧
War(uh-huh), huh(yeah, huh)
战争
Absolutely nothing
完全没有
It ain't nothing but a heart breaker
它只会让人心碎
War, it's got one friend, that's the undertaker
战争 只是殡葬业的朋友
Oh, war
战争
Has shattered many a young man's dreams
已经粉碎了很多年轻人的梦想
Made him disabled, bitter and mean
让他变得残疾 痛苦和卑鄙
谢谢 米奇·曼托
Thanks, Mickey Mantle.
To spend fighting wars each day
每天都在打仗
War can't give life
战争不能给予生命
It can only take it away, oh
它只能带走生命
War, huh, good God, y'all
战争啊 上帝啊 你们说
What is it good for?
它有什么好处
Absolutely nothing
完全没有
Say it again
再说一遍
War, oh Lord
战争 天呐
What is it good for
有什么好处呢
You tell me
你告诉我
Say it, say it, say it, say it
说啊说啊
War, huh, good God, y'all
战争 上帝啊
What is it good for
有什么好处呢
我得回家了
I gotta get home.
你不把啤酒喝完吗
You're not gonna finish your beer?
干杯
Cheers.
恐怕这不是你想象中的
I'm afraid this isn't the bonding moment
父子亲密时刻 孩子
you think it is, son.
马克
Mark.
感谢你的参与
Thank you for your participation.
给
Here you go.
好吧
All right.
你总是有家可回的 泰森
You always have a home, Tyson,
除非你自己不愿意
unless you choose not to.
所以你自己选吧
So, make your choice.
-今晚其实  -挺过瘾的
- Tonight was actually... - Cathartic.
如果你不介意的话 我要回家了
I'm gonna head home, if that's all right.
等等
Hold up.
我该把这钱扣到我欠你的账上
Should probably put that towards what I owe you.
不不不 一码归一码
No, no, no, here. That's apples, this is oranges.
去买台新的割草机吧
Buy a new lawnmower.
-阿曼德  -嗯
- Armand. - Yes?
我们的协议仍然没变
Our arrangement still holds.
妈的
Fuck.
乔安妮
-嗨  -嗨 我很抱歉
- Hey. - Hey. I'm sorry,
我知道都凌晨了
I know it's really early.
不 没关系 我在 我没事
No, it's okay. I'm here, I'm fine.
如果你想和乔谈谈 我觉得你最好
If you want to talk to Joe, I think it's best
-现在就去  -嗯 好
- that you do it right now. - Yeah, okay.
-他还能说话吗  -不能
- Can he talk? - No.
但大家都在过来的路上了
But everyone's on their way over.
他快死了 德怀特 要不行了
He's dying, Dwight. He's shutting down.
我们的兄弟乔快死了
Our brother Joe is dying.
他能听到我们说话 所以你 说吧
He can hear us, so you-- you just talk.
之前我问他要不要我给你打电话时
And he squeezed my hand before when I asked him
他还捏了我的手
if he wanted me to call you.
跟他说说话吧 他毕竟是你弟弟
Just talk to him. He's your little brother.
好
Okay.
嘿 乔伊
Hey, Joey.
乔 我是你哥哥 德怀特
Joe. It's your brother, Dwight.
你生病了 我很抱歉
Hey, I'm sorry you're not feeling good.
我对很多事都感到抱歉
I'm sorry about a lot of things.
前几天我在想复活节那事儿
I was thinking the other day about Easter.
你还记得吗
You remember that time
老爷子让我们去拿八角饼干
Pops had us pick up some of those anise cookies?
米兰诺夫人给的
From Mrs. Milano?
我抄了近路
And I took that shortcut.
有 有个人
There was-- there was this guy.
很壮实 你记得不
He was heavy set, you know...
穿着白色的衣服 白胡子 白头发
dressed in white, you know, white beard, white hair.
你还记得你问了他什么吗
Do you remember what you asked him?
记得 你看 他听到了
Yes. Look, he hears you.
你问他是不是上帝
You asked him if he was God.
还记得他说了什么吗
Remember what he said?
我们俩都站在那里 像看海市蜃楼一样看着他
We were both standing there, looking at him like a mirage.
他说 如果你说我是上帝
And he said, "Well, if you say I'm God,
当你看到祂的时候 祂一定就长这样
when you saw him, then that's who he must be."
总之
Anyway...
如果你看到了 这个人
if you see this guy...
我觉得他没问题
I think he's okay.
我觉得你应该跟他一起走
And I think you should go with him.
还有
And...
咱们
you and me...
待会儿再叙 乔伊
we'll catch up later, Joe.
曼尼 你整晚上都跑哪去了
Manny, where the hell have you been all night?
回屋里去 拉里
Get back in the house. Larry!
拉里
Larry.
I ain't gonna stop just because I get old
我不会因为老了就放弃
我们五分钟后要和那个房地产经纪人
We have that Zoom meeting with that real estate agent
-开视频会议  -我们已经有家了
- in five minutes. - We already have a home.
And doing what I'm told
做着别人告诉我要做的事
I'll be six feet deep before I get cold
在我变冷之前 我会被埋在六英尺深的地方
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
我在考虑染发
I'm thinking about dyeing my hair.
-什么颜色  -琥珀色
- What color? - Amber.
那就染吧 做你自己
So, do it. Go ahead, be yourself.
-有何不可  -做我自己
- Why not? - Be myself.
做你自己
Be yourself.
我喜欢 做我自己
I like that. Be myself.
我常常想起过去的美好时光
and I used to think about the good old days...
殡仪馆
下集预告
塔尔萨之王
过去的美好时光并没有那么美好
the good old days were not really that good.
下集预告
塔尔萨之王
现在 我意识到我错过了什么
Now, I realize what I missed--
错过了看着我女儿长大 结婚
seeing my daughter grow up, get married.
没有我的保护 她就这么长大了
And she did all that without me protecting her.
布莱克·麦克亚当 他们会杀了任何挡道的人
Black Macadam, they'll kill anyone that gets in their way.
好父亲就该这么做
So, that's what a good father does--
保护他们负责监护的孩子
protects the ones they're responsible for.